# **Derrick Daniel Mwikyo**

Kampala, Uganda



mwikyoderrick@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/mwikyo

# **Summary**

Proactive and passionate about good and quality service provision. Ready to get work done at all times. I take the old and new tools, use them to make those whose lives and user experiences I must change, satisfied, excited and ready for more.

Some of my tools: Slack and Teams, Jira, VS Code, Android Studio, Datagrip, Google Apps (docs, sheets, slides, meet, calendars), HTML/CSS/Bootstrap, Honey comb, Grafana Loki, Datadog, Postman, Github, Chrome, Javascript, SQL/PostgreSQL and a bunch more. Udemy, YouTube and Google (yes, the learning is part of it all).

## **Experience**



### Product Support Associate

#### SafeBoda

Jul 2021 - Present (1 year 2 months +)

°Escalate unresolved bug reports and issues to the engineering teams, team managers and other internal teams to ensure great teamwork.

°Train internal teams troubleshooting techniques, problem solving, technical support, issue escalation methods, analytical skills, reporting writing, customer satisfaction, and how to provide quality feedback to customers.

°Work with logs and metrics to study performance, identify patterns and make recommendations.

Research and identify bugs and other issues and recommend possible solutions to internal teams.

Document technical knowledge for study purposes to new team members and other internal teams.

"Write reports and provide accurate feedback to internal teams and sometimes, customers.

°Write SQL/PostgreSQL queries to study performance.

°Use API endpoints to solve technical issues and automate solutions.

°Work with information technology companies and other third-parties to troubleshoot and resolve issues.

"Work with the Support Team to ensure great customer relationship management.

°Work with the leadership to align company goals, ensure great communication and to track progress.

# Payments Associate

### SafeBoda

Oct 2020 - Jul 2021 (10 months)

°Executed all financial processes as required.

Prepared, submitted, and reviewed payment packages in a timely manner to the finance department.

°Mantained an organized and consistent filing system for project related financial documents.

°Analysed data to study business growth and to find ways to ensure growth.

°Took part in decision making.



#### SafeBoda

Oct 2019 - Mar 2020 (6 months)

- ~Liaised with customers, management, and sales teams to better understand customer needs and recommend appropriate solutions.
- ~Consulted outside parties to resolve inconsistencies and created effective solutions.
- ~Investigated and resolved customer inquiries and complaints.
- ~Handled outbound calls and provided customer service to the company's clients.
- ~Inventory management: marketed and promoted the airtime and food & shop products.

## Communications Officer

### Girl Talk Uganda

Mar 2018 - Oct 2019 (1 year 8 months)

- —Cultivated productive relationships and strong communication with other organisations, securing profitable partnerships.
- —Read, communicated, and analyzed information and guidelines.
- —Wrote features for the organizations' print publications and provided content for the website and social media to promote high-visibility.
- —Prepared, organized and managed project schedules to produce deliverables and meet deadlines.

#### **Education**

# (A) freeCodeCamp

Front-end Dev, Front-end web development 2020 - 2020

HTML, CSS, JAVASCRIPT, REACT, BOOTSTRAP

# Kyambogo University

Bachelor's degree, Development Studies 2015 - 2018

—Broke down and rebuilt my thought processes.

# Nyakasura School

UACE, Secondary School 2013 - 2014

### **Licenses & Certifications**

in Excel for Business Analysts - LinkedIn

# in Learning SQL Programming - LinkedIn

1d38e0e64b568acf71bf8069ec52c60e990aadee3af0a11c58ddae15d39bafad

# Agile Leadership and Resilient Teams - Udemy

UC-d78fb354-4396-43c1-8eb2-c3b2d4b8a0eb

APIs with Postman for Absolute beginners - Udemy

UC-844c553b-4b42-41a0-942d-9a04912e3ed9

REST API Testing, Automation using POSTMAN - Udemy

UC-95a19368-36d7-4446-8b7c-9f50cf3e8eb3

### **Skills**

Web Development • Research • Analytical Skills • Business Analysis • Problem Solving • Technical Support • Information Technology • Communication • Customer Relationship Management (CRM) • Team Leadership

### **Honors & Awards**

■ Bachelor's Degree in Development Studies - Kyambogo University

Dec 2018